<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2016 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:35:54 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Restart docker after archlinux upgrade</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/05/08/restart-docker-after-archlinux-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 09:35:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/05/08/restart-docker-after-archlinux-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>My main reason for avoiding ArchLinux upgrades (sudo pacman -Syu) was because I always needed to reboot my computer, to allow starting docker services after the upgrade. Today, I found the solution is a simple:
systemctl daemon-reload systemctl restart docker  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I broke my archlinux and fixed it</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/04/27/how-i-broke-my-archlinux-and-fixed-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 20:15:15 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/04/27/how-i-broke-my-archlinux-and-fixed-it/</guid>
      <description>Today, new lesson learnt. I needed to test something with Internet Explorer and Edge, so I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded the test images from the Microsoft website, then proceeded to install virtualbox, in my current KDE based ArchLinux desktop (which I love a lot). A simple pacman -S virtualbox perhaps? Yes, except&amp;hellip;
After installing virtualbox, it complained about some missing libssl2.0.0 lib&amp;hellip; so I thought maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t have that installed? I didn&amp;rsquo;t really research it, just installed openssl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The wrong way to sudo su, and the right way</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/04/20/the-wrong-way-to-sudo-su-and-the-right-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 10:34:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/04/20/the-wrong-way-to-sudo-su-and-the-right-way/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve never had a formal training on Linux. My knowledge comes from my experience working on it for the last 12 years, but some things I&#39;ve just learned as simple recipes and never bother looking them up.
One such thing was changing users with sudo. I&#39;ve been doing it as:
sudo su &amp;lt;user&amp;gt; - Notice the dash at the end, which makes provides a &#34;real&#34; environment for &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;, just as if I would have logged in with that user, directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads: a very good load balancing solution</title>
      <link>/blog/2009/01/06/crossroads-a-very-good-load-balancing-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 16:53:02 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2009/01/06/crossroads-a-very-good-load-balancing-solution/</guid>
      <description>Recently Martin Aspeli published a very nice buildout recipe that implements a complete setup for a production Zope/Plone server. One of the key components in that setup is the load balancer, which is implemented using the load balancer capabilities of nginx. Nginx might be a good load balancer, but it has a problem with the way Zope/Plone works: the first page loads, for a newly restarted Plone instance are very slow (especially if the site or the catalogs are big).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Hardy Heron: some things are bad</title>
      <link>/blog/2008/03/28/ubuntu-hardy-heron-some-things-are-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2008 09:53:44 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2008/03/28/ubuntu-hardy-heron-some-things-are-bad/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: always create a root account on Ubuntu. I&#39;ve updated my laptop to Kubuntu Hardy Heron, and while some things worked fine, there are a couple of stupid bugs that chained to make my life hard.
First of all, why did the Network Configuration applet in Settings Manager in KDE saw fit to delete the hostname of my localhost, tibi-laptop, from /etc/hosts? Now I can&#39;t run anything with sudo, as it imediately aborts with an error &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is lame</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</guid>
      <description>I may sound like a fanboy or something, but I&#39;m starting to think that it&#39;s impossible to have a perfect piece of software, especially with larger systems. Two things that happened to me lately that made me think this:
How lame is that Windows doesn&#39;t automount USB sticks when they&#39;re present at boot time? Why would I have to remove+reinsert the stick just so Windows will see the bloody thing? My Kubuntu, of course, handles perfectly everything in this department (at least in my case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brettspielwelt - the free, online boardgame portal</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 09:51:20 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</guid>
      <description>I live in Europe, I&#39;m a geek, so I must also be a boardgame freak. I love games, and especially German style boardgames, with their intricate rules. Unfortunately, there&#39;s not much time to play, and not a lot of people that I can play with. Following a link on boardgamesgeek.com I&#39;ve stumbled on this website, an online portal of boardgames that you can play, something similar to IGS (the Internet Go Server), but that implements loads of boardgames to be played in multiplayer style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting the fans for an HP Compaq NX6125 with Ubuntu Feisty after suspend</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/04/13/starting-the-fans-for-an-hp-compaq-nx6125-with-ubuntu-feisty-after-suspend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2007 09:07:41 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/04/13/starting-the-fans-for-an-hp-compaq-nx6125-with-ubuntu-feisty-after-suspend/</guid>
      <description>In the saga to make my laptop behave as best as I can I&#39;ve encountered a new obstacle: using Ubuntu Feisty Fawn (the beta) with kubuntu-desktop installed and using KDE, I can put the laptop in suspend mode, but the CPU fan won&#39;t turn on when I wake it. After a bit of searching I&#39;ve found out that I need to do:
root@ubuntu:~# echo 0 &amp;gt; /proc/acpi/fan/C262/stateThis starts the fan. Writing 3 in that fan ACPI state will turn off the fan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeciv rediscovered</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 10:22:51 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently &#34;rediscovered&#34; Freeciv. I&#39;m a very casual gamer (15 minutes/day), but also an old, addicted, Civilization fan. Lately I&#39;ve been looking for a nice game to play on my Linux desktops and I&#39;ve found that Freeciv is finally getting some good graphics, as this was my biggest turn off I&#39;ve had with it before. I&#39;ve tried first the SDL client on Windows, but it is buggy and tends to freeze its popup windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onwards to Gnome through Beryl and back to KDE</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/21/onwards-to-gnome-through-beryl-and-back-to-kde/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 18:35:40 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/21/onwards-to-gnome-through-beryl-and-back-to-kde/</guid>
      <description>I like my Linux to stay &#34;on the edge&#34;, I like the excitement of knowing that on the next update you&#39;ll get new or improved software, which happens a lot in the Open Source world. So I&#39;ve updated yesterday my laptop (a Compaq NX 6125) to the yet unreleased Ubuntu Feisty Fawn, an experienced that took almost 24 hours to have a fully working system at the end. I&#39;ll give some details of the problems encountered below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zope buildout quickstart</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/10/zope-buildout-quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2007 22:19:56 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/10/zope-buildout-quickstart/</guid>
      <description>One of the bigger players in the latest move to automate Plone and Zope development and deployment has been buildout, so I figured it&#39;s about time to start learning it and see how it can help me. I&#39;m writing this short recipe as I progress through learning buildout to help me remember this stuff later on.
Installing buildoutThe easiest way to install buildout is to get easy_install (a manager for python packages) on your system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitfall of building python from source on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/10/29/pitfall-of-building-python-from-source-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 12:32:46 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/10/29/pitfall-of-building-python-from-source-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Zope 3.3 doesn&#39;t work well with the python 2.4.4 that comes with Ubuntu Edgy. Something about a readline change somewhere in the python standard library. So I had to build python 2.4.3 from source. Being an impatient being, I haven&#39;t give it much thought and just unpacked the python tarball, hit ./configure and make install. I ended up with python installed in /usr/local/bin/python, which would be really really cool if Ubuntu wouldn&#39;t depend on python and wouldn&#39;t place /usr/local/bin at the beginning of $PATH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dapper &#43; 1 = Edgy</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/10/01/dapper---1--edgy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 11:22:46 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/10/01/dapper---1--edgy/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve upgraded my laptop&#39;s Compaq nx6125 Dapper to Edgy yesterday. These are some of the issues and highlights that I encountered:
The update manager that did the upgrade it is impressive, but the update was not entirely automatically, one of the gtk engine packages kept spewing errors. The update manager was able to go over this incident in the initial phase, but terminated with an error when it was about 95% to finishing the update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kde applications vs Gnome applications</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/23/kde-applications-vs-gnome-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2006 18:22:43 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/23/kde-applications-vs-gnome-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m switching a bunch of Gnome daily used apps to their KDE counterparts. Namely I&#39;ve switched from *Liferea to Akregate, from **GnoCHM to KchmViewer and from ***GIMP to Krita (Gimp sucks too much for me in terms of workflow, while Krita is more conventional and less awkward from some points of view). I&#39;m using already using Konversation for IRC (much better then XChat, I&#39;d use Chatzilla but it doesn&#39;t go to the systray), Tellico to keep a database of PS2 games and K3b for burning dvds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online tools to check DNS</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/22/online-tools-to-check-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 13:53:40 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/22/online-tools-to-check-dns/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then I need to check the dns settings for some servers that I look after. Not being an expert, I use these two sites frequently to check that I&#39;m not doing anything stupid:
http://www.dnsstuff.com/http://www.dnsreport.com
My preferate is dnsreport.com, but I always forget its name and its pagerank on google is not too high. So I&#39;m doing my really really tiny bit in lifting up its page rank by linking to it on this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short checklist for Postfix &#43; MySQL &#43; Dovecot &#43; SASL authentication on Fedora</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/16/short-checklist-for-postfix---mysql---dovecot---sasl-authentication-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2006 21:56:19 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/16/short-checklist-for-postfix---mysql---dovecot---sasl-authentication-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>1. Postfix needs to be rebuilt with Mysql enabled
Follow this tutorial: http://postfix.wiki.xs4all.nl/index.php?title=Virtual_Users_and_Domains_with_Courier-IMAP_and_MySQL
This one also helps: Virtual Users And Domains With Postfix, Courier And MySQL (Fedora Core 5) | HowtoForge - Linux Howtos and Tutorials
2. Instal cyrus-sasl and cyrus-sasl-sql.
Configure /etc/sysconfig/saslauthd to run with the rimap mechanism 3. Start saslauthd</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying KDE as the main work desktop</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/02/trying-kde-as-the-main-work-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 20:38:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/02/trying-kde-as-the-main-work-desktop/</guid>
      <description>Until a year ago, when I had my first hands-on experience with Ubuntu, I was a KDE fan. I still admire the desktop and follow closely the development, but I was so impressed at that time by the uniformity and visual appeal that Gnome, under Ubuntu, offered, that I switched. Recently I found the Gnome desktop to be a bit on the slow on my laptop, so I&#39;ve tried several lighter window managers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improve Plone-based website performance with simple Apache caching</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/08/30/improve-plone-based-website-performance-with-simple-apache-caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 00:38:53 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/08/30/improve-plone-based-website-performance-with-simple-apache-caching/</guid>
      <description>I won&#39;t go too much into details, and this is more for my own personal reference, but using this short recipe I was able to increase by up to 100 times the performance of a plone based website. For a lot more details and more advanced techniques for caching, integration with squid and cachefu, visit the Plone documentation HowTo section.
 The website hosts mostly news updates, and is edited mostly by an editorial staff, under a 24 hours cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short guide to dns with bind on Fedora</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/08/23/short-guide-to-dns-with-bind-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 09:40:13 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/08/23/short-guide-to-dns-with-bind-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m replacing a tinydns server with bind9, so I may as well put the setup here, as future reference.
First,
yum install bind-chroot
to install the chrooted bind server.
Next, edit the /var/named/chroot/etc/named.conf
options {
directory &#34;/var/named&#34;;
dump-file &#34;/var/named/data/cache_dump.db&#34;;
statistics-file &#34;/var/named/data/named_stats.txt&#34;;
recursion no;
};
//root global
//life
zone &#34;life.org.ro&#34; {
type master;
file &#34;/etc/db.life.org.ro&#34;;
notify yes;
};
zone &#34;0.0.127.in-addr.arpa&#34; {
type master;
file &#34;/etc/db.localhost&#34;;
allow-update { none; };
};
zone &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miniguide to openldap</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/08/13/miniguide-to-openldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2006 00:25:52 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/08/13/miniguide-to-openldap/</guid>
      <description>LDAP is a lot easier then one might think at first sight. First, reading this short introduction to LDAP will tell us that LDAP is just an object database, that holds trees of objects and schemas of those objects. This is nice and easy for anyone acustomed to ZODB and Archetypes.
Next, installing. The OpenLDAP server on Debian is called slapd, so apt-get install slapd. After that, run dpkg-reconfigure -plow slapd which will allow reconfiguring the domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Games for Linux</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/08/12/games-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 13:28:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/08/12/games-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Following link from the PyPi, I&#39;ve stumbled upon this page: http://emhsoft.net/index.html
The abstract shooters on that page are very nice. Also, a few of those games are implemented with pygame ;-) . </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite development environment</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/07/22/my-favorite-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2006 19:54:38 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/07/22/my-favorite-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&#39;d add some words about the development environment that I feel most comfortable with.
First, I use AGX for most of my plone development. It&#39;s useful as a quick skeleton generator, but also as a way to structure the content. To generate the UML files I use Poseidon Community Edition. Up until recently it was buggy, and I still consider it to be, but I learned what to do so I won&#39;t trigger the bugs (quick tip: don&#39;t ever rename tagged values, delete it and recreate it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>