<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2016 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:26:44 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier development when dealing with docker-compose stacks</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/12/13/easier-development-when-dealing-with-docker-compose-stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:26:44 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/12/13/easier-development-when-dealing-with-docker-compose-stacks/</guid>
      <description>For some time I&#39;ve had to deal with two separate, docker-compose based application stacks. One of them combining a Ruby on Rails app with a whole suite of ElasticSearch nodes, sidekiq worker, Postgresql, nginx, the whole shebang. Another is just a plain Zope/Plone stack, but the difficulties remain the same: when I wanted to do production debugging or just plain development using that environment, I needed something that can be started manually, in the whole stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use pgloader to migrate sqlite database to postgresql</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/06/13/how-to-use-pgloader-to-migrate-sqlite-database-to-postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 23:49:14 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/06/13/how-to-use-pgloader-to-migrate-sqlite-database-to-postgresql/</guid>
      <description>I needed to migrate a Kotti database, from its default sqlite file store, to Postgresql. Clued in by StackOverflow, I&#39;ve tried using pgloader, but the version coming with Ubuntu is old: 2.x instead of the brand new 3.x. But the jump to 3.x meant a switch in programming languages as well: the new one is written in Lisp. I didn&#39;t want to install and compile the whole Lisp bundle just to run pgloader and I didn&#39;t find a binary distribution either, and after a recent exposure to Docker, I thought I&#39;ll give the dockerized version of pgloader a try.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>