<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2019 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is lame</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</guid>
      <description>I may sound like a fanboy or something, but I&#39;m starting to think that it&#39;s impossible to have a perfect piece of software, especially with larger systems. Two things that happened to me lately that made me think this:
How lame is that Windows doesn&#39;t automount USB sticks when they&#39;re present at boot time? Why would I have to remove+reinsert the stick just so Windows will see the bloody thing? My Kubuntu, of course, handles perfectly everything in this department (at least in my case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brettspielwelt - the free, online boardgame portal</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 09:51:20 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</guid>
      <description>I live in Europe, I&#39;m a geek, so I must also be a boardgame freak. I love games, and especially German style boardgames, with their intricate rules. Unfortunately, there&#39;s not much time to play, and not a lot of people that I can play with. Following a link on boardgamesgeek.com I&#39;ve stumbled on this website, an online portal of boardgames that you can play, something similar to IGS (the Internet Go Server), but that implements loads of boardgames to be played in multiplayer style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeciv rediscovered</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 10:22:51 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently &#34;rediscovered&#34; Freeciv. I&#39;m a very casual gamer (15 minutes/day), but also an old, addicted, Civilization fan. Lately I&#39;ve been looking for a nice game to play on my Linux desktops and I&#39;ve found that Freeciv is finally getting some good graphics, as this was my biggest turn off I&#39;ve had with it before. I&#39;ve tried first the SDL client on Windows, but it is buggy and tends to freeze its popup windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embeding the Gecko engine in Python applications</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/10/embeding-the-gecko-engine-in-python-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2007 18:28:29 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/10/embeding-the-gecko-engine-in-python-applications/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve got to deploy a new desktop based application, created, of course, with Zope 3. When you&#39;ve got a hammer, everything looks like a nail, indeed. This application uses HTML and CSS as its presentation layer (right, it&#39;s a web page), with a bit of Ajax thrown in. Due do time constraints, I&#39;m not even trying to get it to work properly on Internet Explorer (although it looks about 90% right, but I have some problems with Javascript), so I won&#39;t be embeding the Internet Explorer this time engine in my Python application, I&#39;ll just try to get the Gecko rendering engine, the one used in Firefox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Plone (or Zope) in debug mode under Windows</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/10/04/start-plone-or-zope-in-debug-mode-under-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2006 17:58:54 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/10/04/start-plone-or-zope-in-debug-mode-under-windows/</guid>
      <description>Lifted from #plone:
bin/runzope.bat -X &#34;debug-mode=on&#34; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing frameworks and wxPython</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/06/printing-frameworks-and-wxpython/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 16:48:34 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/06/printing-frameworks-and-wxpython/</guid>
      <description>As hard as I have tried to find, there&#39;s no good printing framework for wxPython. wxEasyPrinting sucks so much for anything more then simple text (for example, the table cells don&#39;t support specifying a height). Generating PDF files with a toolkit such as ReportLab (even with Platypus) is harder then it should be, especially when there&#39;s no ready made higher level framework. This page explores some of the common printing solutions on Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Microsoft Word as a Windows service</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/01/running-microsoft-word-as-a-windows-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2006 13:09:44 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/01/running-microsoft-word-as-a-windows-service/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, this is not recommended by Microsoft, but they have some pointers on how to achieve this on their website. How to configure Office applications to run under the interactive user accountConsiderations for server-side Automation of OfficeI ran through the steps in the first article and I can attest that it&#39;s possible to use Microsoft Word to generate, for example, PDF files by printing them from a service. I have the feeling that most of those steps are not needed if Word is not accessed as a COM service, and all is needed is to create a new user, start and configure Word to have a running instance and then configure the service to run as that user.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>