<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fun on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/fun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fun on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2019 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 09:51:20 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brettspielwelt - the free, online boardgame portal</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2007 09:51:20 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/03/brettspielwelt---the-free-online-boardgame-portal/</guid>
      <description>I live in Europe, I&#39;m a geek, so I must also be a boardgame freak. I love games, and especially German style boardgames, with their intricate rules. Unfortunately, there&#39;s not much time to play, and not a lot of people that I can play with. Following a link on boardgamesgeek.com I&#39;ve stumbled on this website, an online portal of boardgames that you can play, something similar to IGS (the Internet Go Server), but that implements loads of boardgames to be played in multiplayer style.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll for initiative, monkey boy!</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/24/roll-for-initiative-monkey-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 21:07:12 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/24/roll-for-initiative-monkey-boy/</guid>
      <description>I thought I&#39;d put a link here for a source of great entertainment of mine: The Knights of the Dinner Table. Hope you&#39;ll be as entertained as I am every time I&#39;m watching them or reading the KODT comic strip.
And another link: Barbarian Prince, a downloadable solitaire game, a mixture of boardgame/RPG/choose your own adventure. I found a review of this game in the KODT comics magazine, but there are a couple of other games there, for two players or solitaire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeciv rediscovered</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2007 10:22:51 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/20/freeciv-rediscovered/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently &#34;rediscovered&#34; Freeciv. I&#39;m a very casual gamer (15 minutes/day), but also an old, addicted, Civilization fan. Lately I&#39;ve been looking for a nice game to play on my Linux desktops and I&#39;ve found that Freeciv is finally getting some good graphics, as this was my biggest turn off I&#39;ve had with it before. I&#39;ve tried first the SDL client on Windows, but it is buggy and tends to freeze its popup windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Plone quote ever</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/09/22/best-plone-quote-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2006 18:46:55 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/09/22/best-plone-quote-ever/</guid>
      <description>[18:43] &amp;lt;julesa&amp;gt; newbie39: To paraphrase Jon Ribbens &#34;PHP is a minor evil perpetrated and created by incompetent amateurs, whereas Plone s a great and insidious evil, perpetrated by skilled but perverted professionals.&#34;
I admit I love being evil! :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Games for Linux</title>
      <link>/blog/2006/08/12/games-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 13:28:05 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2006/08/12/games-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>Following link from the PyPi, I&#39;ve stumbled upon this page: http://emhsoft.net/index.html
The abstract shooters on that page are very nice. Also, a few of those games are implemented with pygame ;-) . </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>