<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ajax on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/ajax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ajax on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2016 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ajax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is lame</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</guid>
      <description>I may sound like a fanboy or something, but I&#39;m starting to think that it&#39;s impossible to have a perfect piece of software, especially with larger systems. Two things that happened to me lately that made me think this:
How lame is that Windows doesn&#39;t automount USB sticks when they&#39;re present at boot time? Why would I have to remove+reinsert the stick just so Windows will see the bloody thing? My Kubuntu, of course, handles perfectly everything in this department (at least in my case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Zope 3 AJAX viewlet manager</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/28/a-zope-3-ajax-viewlet-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 19:24:51 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/28/a-zope-3-ajax-viewlet-manager/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve finally got tired of writing small fragments of JavaScript code and views to be able to make different areas updatable through ajax for my current Zope 3 application. Plus, when I&#39;ve started writing this application, I&#39;ve started doing the layout with viewlets and managers, and it seems that for each viewlet that I&#39;m creating I have to have a way to get its content through AJAX, which means having a page available for it, and this is very odd, as it almost defeats the point of having viewlets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh meat for programmers</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/16/fresh-meat-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2007 20:52:16 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/16/fresh-meat-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve just discovered (or rediscovered) some resources that I think are important enough to highlight here.
The Zope Corporation has several eggs that are not published in the svn.zope.org subversion repository, eggs located at download.zope.org. There are several very interesting packages there, including some to build an intranet. I&#39;ll definately have a look at them.I&#39;ve rediscovered OpenJSAN, a Javascript repository full of goodies.
And its really nice Planet Javascript
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FCKEditor in Ajax views on Zope 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/12/using-fckeditor-in-ajax-views-on-zope-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 21:14:48 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/12/using-fckeditor-in-ajax-views-on-zope-3/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working on a new, AJAX based application for a friend, which will run under Zope 3. Being a rather &#34;CMS-ish&#34; type of application, I need to provide an easy way to edit some rich text fields. I&#39;ve settled on the FCKEditor, for which there is an already packaged library as zope.html (also depends on zope.file). I would have used TinyMCE, but I hit on a problem: all these visual editors have difficulties when loaded in &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>