<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2017 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 09:21:46 -0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you really need that metadata column?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/01/08/do-you-really-need-that-metadata-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 09:21:46 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/01/08/do-you-really-need-that-metadata-column/</guid>
      <description>It is one of the tenets of Plone optimization that brain.getObject() should be avoided and instead new metadata columns should be defined, to pass have that information in the brain. In the interest of keeping the ZODB free of junk and avoid duplication of information, I argue that it is possible sometimes to avoid polluting the catalog and instead use the information stored in the index itself.&amp;nbsp;
As an example: when exploring collective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier development when dealing with docker-compose stacks</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/12/13/easier-development-when-dealing-with-docker-compose-stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 09:26:44 -0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/12/13/easier-development-when-dealing-with-docker-compose-stacks/</guid>
      <description>For some time I&#39;ve had to deal with two separate, docker-compose based application stacks. One of them combining a Ruby on Rails app with a whole suite of ElasticSearch nodes, sidekiq worker, Postgresql, nginx, the whole shebang. Another is just a plain Zope/Plone stack, but the difficulties remain the same: when I wanted to do production debugging or just plain development using that environment, I needed something that can be started manually, in the whole stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abusing Plone Content Rules to allow Site Admin customizations of sent emails</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/08/31/abusing-plone-content-rules-to-allow-site-admin-customizations-of-sent-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 08:12:43 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/08/31/abusing-plone-content-rules-to-allow-site-admin-customizations-of-sent-emails/</guid>
      <description>This would be a sort of tutorial on how to implement a new plone.app.contentrules Trigger Event, how to write a new plone.stringinterp variable substitutor and how to trigger the event from a browser page (or z3c.form).
This allows configuring a new trigger event from the Content Rules Plone control panel configlet and to assign a new Email action, with customizable body template.
Let&#39;s say our task is to implement a contact form:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearningJourney: A Zope 3 tutorial</title>
      <link>/blog/2009/01/16/learningjourney-a-zope-3-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 20:16:42 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2009/01/16/learningjourney-a-zope-3-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Last year, in December, I held a 3 day Zope 3 training for about 10 Zope 2 and Python programmers. For this training I had prepared a 50 pages booklet with some tutorials and reference information (most of it written by me especially for this occasion). The feedback was pretty positive, but only time will tell if I was succesful or not with my training.
I have published the training material on Google Code in a project called z3ergo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichText control with wxpython: saving, loading and converting from internal XML to HTML</title>
      <link>/blog/2008/10/08/richtext-control-with-wxpython-saving-loading-and-converting-from-internal-xml-to-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 17:14:46 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2008/10/08/richtext-control-with-wxpython-saving-loading-and-converting-from-internal-xml-to-html/</guid>
      <description>I tend to be an angry caveman these days (see my previous post) and this doesn&#39;t lead to too much clear thinking. I&#39;ve been dealing with the wx.richtext.RichTextCtrl for the past couple of days and I think I&#39;m now close to finishing the tasks that I set myself to do with it. I&#39;m trying to run a bunch of richtext controls on the same page, that would increase their size and show a toolbar when focused.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>