<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on The Plone Expanse</title>
    <link>/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on The Plone Expanse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>@2016 Tiberiu Ichim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 14:38:42 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid Internet Explorer and stupid IE bugs</title>
      <link>/blog/2008/09/15/stupid-internet-explorer-and-stupid-ie-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 14:38:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2008/09/15/stupid-internet-explorer-and-stupid-ie-bugs/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m placing the finishing touches on a web application I&#39;ve been writing on and off for the last year. At last, I&#39;ve reached Internet Explorer bugs, which are usually the last to be fixed. Among several other stupid but documented bugs, I&#39;ve found one which I couldn&#39;t find documented in a shallow search on Google: it seems IE has an algorithm for comparing strings that is different then the one that is used internally when sorting an array of strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with jQuery version 1.2.2 and getJSON</title>
      <link>/blog/2008/01/27/problem-with-jquery-version-1.2.2-and-getjson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2008 14:53:25 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2008/01/27/problem-with-jquery-version-1.2.2-and-getjson/</guid>
      <description>It took me a couple of hours to track this (I was just starting a new project using jQuery), but I finally nailed it: jQuery version 1.2.2 has a problem with loading JSON data from absolute urls. Use the trunk version and you&#39;ll be fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is lame</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2007 08:24:14 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/05/08/software-is-lame/</guid>
      <description>I may sound like a fanboy or something, but I&#39;m starting to think that it&#39;s impossible to have a perfect piece of software, especially with larger systems. Two things that happened to me lately that made me think this:
How lame is that Windows doesn&#39;t automount USB sticks when they&#39;re present at boot time? Why would I have to remove+reinsert the stick just so Windows will see the bloody thing? My Kubuntu, of course, handles perfectly everything in this department (at least in my case).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One issue using Prototype&#39;s Ajax form submission with Zope 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/03/25/one-issue-using-prototypes-ajax-form-submission-with-zope-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 16:08:02 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/03/25/one-issue-using-prototypes-ajax-form-submission-with-zope-3/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve found a weird issue while trying to debug why on of my Ajax loaded forms wasn&#39;t, apparently, properly validated. Even though that the schema specified that the fields are required, the form action would get executed as if the validation wouldn&#39;t have been done or the request was properly validated. I thought at first that there&#39;s an issue with the form class/handling itself, but after some testing I came to the conclusion that it has to be the way I&#39;m doing the AJAX request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I hate brackets! (or rants of a JavaScript novice programmer)</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/27/i-hate-brackets-or-rants-of-a-javascript-novice-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 17:09:31 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/27/i-hate-brackets-or-rants-of-a-javascript-novice-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Javascript is nice, I&#39;m having fun building this Zope3/Ajax based application that I&#39;m working on right now. What I don&#39;t enjoy is the forest of non-alphanumeric characters that has started to clog my code. I&#39;m really a novice when it comes to Javascript, most of my professional programming has been done with other languages, but look for example at this fragment of code:
 for (i=0; i&amp;lt; parent.childNodes.length; i++) {</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh meat for programmers</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/16/fresh-meat-for-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2007 20:52:16 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/16/fresh-meat-for-programmers/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve just discovered (or rediscovered) some resources that I think are important enough to highlight here.
The Zope Corporation has several eggs that are not published in the svn.zope.org subversion repository, eggs located at download.zope.org. There are several very interesting packages there, including some to build an intranet. I&#39;ll definately have a look at them.I&#39;ve rediscovered OpenJSAN, a Javascript repository full of goodies.
And its really nice Planet Javascript
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FCKEditor in Ajax views on Zope 3</title>
      <link>/blog/2007/02/12/using-fckeditor-in-ajax-views-on-zope-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2007 21:14:48 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2007/02/12/using-fckeditor-in-ajax-views-on-zope-3/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m working on a new, AJAX based application for a friend, which will run under Zope 3. Being a rather &#34;CMS-ish&#34; type of application, I need to provide an easy way to edit some rich text fields. I&#39;ve settled on the FCKEditor, for which there is an already packaged library as zope.html (also depends on zope.file). I would have used TinyMCE, but I hit on a problem: all these visual editors have difficulties when loaded in &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>